From this distant vantage point the earth might not seem of any particular interest
But for us it's different
Consider again that dut
That's here
That's home
That's us
On it
Everyone you love
Everyone you know
Everyone you ever heard of every human being who ever was lived out their lives
The aggregate of our joy and suffering
Thousands of confident religions ideologies and economic doctrines
Every hunter and forager
Every heroe and coward every creator and destroyer of civilization every king and peasant
Every young couple in love every mother and father hopeful child
Inventor and explorer every teacher of morals everycorrupt politician every
Superstar every
Supreme leader every saint and sinner in the history of our species
Lived there on a mote of dust
Suspended in a sunbeam
The earth is a very small stage in a vast
Cosmic arena
Think of the rivers of blood builled by all those generals and emperors
So that in glory and triumph they could become the momentary masters
Of affraction of a dott
Think of the endless cruelties visited by the inhabitants of one corner of this pixel on the scarcely distinguishable inhabitants of some other corner how frequent their misunderstandings how eager they are to kill one another how fervent their hatreds our
Posturings
Our imagined
Self-importance the delusion that we have some privileged position in the universe are challenged by this point of pale light
Our planet
Is a lonely speck in the great
Enveloping cosmic dark
In our
Obscurity
In all this vastness
There is no hint that help will come from elsewhere to save us from ourselves the earth is the only world known so far to harbour life
There is nowhere else at least in the near future to which our species could migrate
Is it
Yes
Settle not yet
Like it or not for the moment the earth is where we make our stand it has been said that astronomy is a humbling and
Character-building experience there is perhaps no better demonstration of the folly of human conceits
Than this distant image of our tiny world
To me it underscores our responsibility to deal more kindly with one another and to preserve and cherish the pale blue dut the only home we've ever known